

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO · SUMMER COOP 2022

□ (226) 505-3010 | SauravLaurikant | 1 auravLaurikant | 2 auravLaurikant | 2 auravLaurikant | 2 auravLaurikant | 2 auravLaurikant | 3 auravLaurik

# **Summary**

**Programming** Proven experience in developing bussiness-critical applications. Architectured company wide API's and automation solutions

Taught programming fundamentals as a teaching assistant. Developed interactive coding modules for students during pandemic

Languages: Python, JavaScript, C++, Matlab, HTML, CSS, LT-X. Tech: React, Node, Express, OAuth, Git, SQL, MongoDB, GraphQL

**Adaptibility** Showcased rapid learning ability by applying developer tools while digitizing signode's operations and integrating its ERP system

# Work Experience \_

Signode Canada Markham, Canada

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING - CONTINUOUS IMPROVEMENT

Jan. 2021 - May. 2021 | Sept. 2021 - Cont.

- · Led the transition of signode's operation (e-commerce, shipping) to a digititized paperless platform. Achieving 25% reduction in yearly costs
- Boosted customer service productivity by 50% by speeding up order entries to \$100k+ worth consumables per week. Developed an EDI platform that analyses purchase order PDFs and consumes SAP ariba APIs to create entries compatible with our ERP system
- Developed complex python algorithms to parse data from PDFs through precise coordinate and pattern recognition. Optimizing parsing speed to <1s for 50+ page objects, while uploading data to MongoDB and microsoft's OneDrive to create RESTful APIs
- · Leveraged the ability of the algorithm to profit signode \$300k worth of inventory backlogs by OCR parsing 8000+ scans and images from past year

## **University Of Waterloo - Engineering**

Waterloo, Canada

Online Teaching Assistant - Computer Programming

May. 2020 - Sept. 2020

- Held computer classes and coding practice sessions in C++ and Matlab for first-year engineering students. Verified and marked code submissions
- · Developed 100+ unit tests in C++ and python's pexpect library to automate verification of student code submissions on marmoset server
- Prototyped and deployed websites to enhance student's learning experience. Used ReatJs and NodeJs to convert mock-ups to useable web presence
- · Analyzed attendance and activeness data of 200+ students across the faculty. Actively provided detailed reports and trends to professors

Tesla Motors Canada ULC Toronto, Canada

MANUFACTURING PLANNING ASSISTANT

Sept. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Developed and implemented a new planning strategy that reduced manufacturing planning time by 20% and paper usage by 8500 sheets/yr
- Utilized strong Python skills to create MRP Forecast and to filter out manufacturing plan history that reduced part repeatability by 40%
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams (design, quality, sales and production) and manufactured 700+ unique parts for Tesla's lithium-ion battery production line and liquid dispensing pneumatic pumps, focusing on manufacturability, product quality and cost reductions

### **Entrepreneurship Society**

Waterloo, Canada

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

May. 2019 - Sept. 2019

- · Developed user-oriented visuals and UI features using ReactJs and RESTful routing. Integrated new interfaces with back-end systems like NodeJs
- · Coordinating user research and user testing efforts, created assets such as icons and visuals for projects using Adobe Photoshop and Figma
- · Worked closely with Social media and marketing team. Prototyped and published new Sponsorship packages with new visual features

Tircon Corp, Canada Hamilton, Canada

**DIMENSION CONTROL QUALITY ENGINEER** 

Jan. 2019 - May. 2019

- · Performed dimensional validation using CMM and PC DMIS, conducted gauge R&R study and prepared control and containment plans
- · Performed tolerance analysis to ensure success in high-volume production and manufacturing of the new Dodge-RAM step-pad

# **Projects**

### **Yelp-Camp Web Application**

Fall 2020

Tech Stack: JavaScript, HTML, Bootstrap, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Link to GitHub

- · Designed a website to review and locate campgrounds using html and JS. Implemented RESTful routing connecting to login and editing features
- Developed a back-end parser (NodeJs, ExpressJs) to interpret and manipulate data stored in MongoDB and to consume API from Google maps

#### **Path-Finding Visualizer and Twitter Surveillance**

Summer 2020

Tech Stack: PYTHON, PYGAME, TWITTER API, TWEEPY Link to GitHub

- · Built python application for visualizing path-finding and maze-generation A\* algorithm. Wrote a 10 pg research on optimization of path-finding
- Twitter bot that stores real time tweet data closely related to vaccine hesitancy, labeling every tweet as pos, neg using NLP and SVM classifier

# **Education**

## **University Of Waterloo**

Ontario · Canada Sept. 2018 - Present

B.S. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

n

· Achieved Excellent academic standing through courses in Programming, Circuits and Instruments, Mechanics and Material design